ROHIT JAIN

Software Engineer

Software Engineer with 1+ year of experience. Have worked on Amazon Pay's core service having experience in all stages of software development cycles including technical design, development, debugging & release. Proficient in taking ownership, going above and beyond to Delivering results.

Mobile: +91 9079327009

rohitjain18005@gmail. com

therohitjain.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Engineer

Aug 2021 - Present

Amazon

- Working in Amazon Pay's core services team
 - Worked on migrating payment contract service that decreased the latency for contract related calls upto 30% and reduced the OE load on the team upto 20%.
 - Worked on a fast paced live issue that prevented Amazon Pay being disabled by over 51 clients in the IN marketplace.
 - Experienced in application security Threat Analysis & Risk mitigation to get them certified for release.
- Worked on Prime Video International Expansion
 - Worked on automating the process for price change in different countries which resulted in the process from 1 week to 2 days.
 - Worked on launching Prime Video in local currency in Sweden.

Software Developer Engineer Intern

Feb 2021 - July 2021

Amazon

- Worked on updating the string lookup logic for Prime Video which resulted in saving upto 40% in storage for translated strings while launching a new country.
- Worked on an internal automation tool, which acts as an admin dashboard for launching new countries and helps in automating the launch flow based on AWS step functions.

Aug 2020 - January 2021

(Software Engineer) Contractor

Starname

 Working on a React / React Native application that facilitates management of crypto wallet in a user-friendly way.

EDUCATION

Jaypee Institute of Information Technology

July 2017 - June 2021

Bachelors in Computer Science and Engineering Coordinator of the Developer Student Club CGPA 7.3 / 10

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages

Java, JavaScript, Python(Flask)

Front-End

ES6, Typescript, React, Jekyll

Mobile

React Native

Databases

GraphQl, MongoDB, MySQL

Misc

Docker, CI/CD and AWS services(SQS/SNS, DynamoDB)

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Video Games Reading Cooking Open Source

ACHIEVEMENTS

Amazon AWS Raise-Up Buildathon https://devpost.com/soft ware/cloutvocate

PROJECTS

Dev Portfolio Blog (Portfolio theme)

Jekyll , Liquid

Created a minimal jekyll theme for writing blogs and about yourself with features like comments, dark mode, Google analytics. This has over 60 stars on Github and is used by more than 60 users for hosting their portfolios.

github.com/rohitjainoo/dev-portfolio-blog

Recipe App

Angular, Flask, MongoDB

A web application for managing recipes among users.

It features managing dynamic recipes with a well structured codebase with integration tests and CI/CD with Heroku & TravisCI.

therohitjain.com/Recipe-App